<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PTI&#43; | Neuro-Aging: Understanding aging from  R&#43;D&#43;I</title>
    <link>https://pti-neuroaging.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on PTI&#43; | Neuro-Aging: Understanding aging from  R&#43;D&#43;I</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 20:17:01 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pti-neuroaging.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How do Consumers’ Gender and Rational Thinking Affect the Acceptance of Entertainment Social Robots?</title>
      <link>https://pti-neuroaging.github.io/blog/acceptance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 13:40:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pti-neuroaging.github.io/blog/acceptance/</guid>
      <description>In this work, we have evaluated how humans’ gender and degrees of analytical thinking impacted their acceptance of a social robot. Specifically, we designed an experiment in which a TIAGo robot was endowed with the ability to provide several degrees of assistance to participants playing a cognitive game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visiting Parc Sanitari Pere Virgili</title>
      <link>https://pti-neuroaging.github.io/blog/visita-pspv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 13:45:06 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pti-neuroaging.github.io/blog/visita-pspv/</guid>
      <description>A team of researchers from the Perception and Manipulation Laboratory (Institute of Robotics and Industrial Computing) led by Carme Torras visited the Parc Sanitari Pere Virgili intermediate care hospital in Barcelona on October 7th to work on future collaborations in the application of Assistive Robotics within the framework of the PTI+ Neuro-Aging project: Understanding aging from R&amp;amp;D&amp;amp;I.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Eat</title>
      <link>https://pti-neuroaging.github.io/projects/ai-eat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 15:56:43 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pti-neuroaging.github.io/projects/ai-eat/</guid>
      <description>As World’s population is ageing, long-term care for elderly citizens will become an increasing cost for society. To manage these transition healthcare policies are heavily focused on extending the independent life of the elderly, with the dual aim of increasing their quality of life (QoL) and reducing the costs of care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RAADiCal</title>
      <link>https://pti-neuroaging.github.io/projects/raadical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pti-neuroaging.github.io/projects/raadical/</guid>
      <description>Assisted activities by robots in daily life care
Project PLEC2021-007817 funded by MCIN/ AEI /10.13039/501100011033 and by the &amp;ldquo;European Union NextGenerationEU/PRTR
The objective of the project is to help elderly or disabled people to maintain a healthy mental and physical life using intelligent robotics systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ROB-IN</title>
      <link>https://pti-neuroaging.github.io/projects/rob-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pti-neuroaging.github.io/projects/rob-in/</guid>
      <description>Robot for continual personalized assistance able to explain itself
ROB-IB project PLEC2021-007859 funded by MCIN/ AEI /10.13039/501100011033 and by the European Union NextGenerationEU/PRTRT.
Robots are increasingly becoming a part of our daily lives and they are deemed to be a very effective tool to address current societal issues.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
